<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- This may be a little TEI-esque, but I tried to not just make this TEI. I played a lot with persname and placename tags, which I borrowed from TEI. Hopefully you'll allow it -->
<book>
    <titlestatment>
        <title type="main">Moby-Dick</title>, or, <title type="alternate">The Whale</title>
       </titlestatment>
        <page id="1">
            <header>
                <chapter id="1" rend="all-caps">CHAPTER I. <title type="chapter">LOOMINGS.</title></chapter>
            </header>
            <p><word rend="all-caps">CALL</word> me <persname id="Ishmael">Ishmael</persname>. Some years ago—never mind how long
                precisely—having little or no money in my purse, and nothing particular to interest me
                on shore, I thought I would sail about a little and see the <placename id="ocean">watery part of the world</placename>. It
                is a way I have of driving off the spleen, and regulating the circulation. Whenever I
                find myself growing grim about the mouth; whenever it is a damp, drizzly <time id="november">November</time> in my
                soul; whenever I find myself involuntarily pausing before coffin warehouses, and
                bringing up the rear of every funeral I meet; and especially whenever my hypos get such
                an upper hand of me, that it requires a strong moral principle to prevent me from
                deliberately stepping into the street, and methodically knocking people's hats off—then,
                I account it <time id="high time">high time</time> to get to <placename id="ocean">sea</placename> as soon as I can. This is my substitute for pistol
                and ball. With a philosophical flourish <persname id="Cato">Cato</persname> throws himself upon his sword; I quietly
                take to the ship. There is nothing surprising in this. If they but knew it, almost all
                men in their degree, some time or other, cherish very nearly the same feelings towards
                <placename id="ocean">the ocean</placename> with me. </p>
            <p>There now is your insular <placename id="Manhattoes">city of the Manhattoes</placename>, belted round by
                wharves as <placename id="Andaman Island, Nicobar Island, and Lakshadweep Island">Indian isles</placename>
                <!-- I wasn't sure how to list three different islands as seperate identities within the same element -->
                by coral reefs—commerce surrounds it with her surf. Right and
                left, the streets take you <placename id="ocean">waterward</placename>. Its extreme down-town is the battery, where that
                noble mole is washed by waves, and cooled by breezes, which a few hours previous were
                out of sight of land. Look at the crowds of water-gazers there.</p>
            <p>Circumambulate the city of a dreamy Sabbath afternoon. Go from <placename id="Corlears Hook">Corlears Hook</placename> to <placename id="Coenties Slip">Coenties Slip</placename>, and from thence,
                by</p>
        </page>
</book>
