<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><html>
  <head>
    <title>part0000</title>
    <meta content="abbyy to epub tool, v0.2" name="generator"/>
    <link href="stylesheet.css" type="text/css" rel="stylesheet"/>
    <meta content="application/xhtml+xml; charset=utf-8" http-equiv="Content-Type"/>
  </head>
  <body>
    <div class="body">
      <div class="pages" id="pages"/>
      <p> Memoir of Sergei O    </p>
      <p> Yesterday Down at the Canal         </p>
      <p> Poem en forme de saw         </p>
      <p> For the Chinese New Year &amp; For Bill Berkson</p>
      <p> Poem ...</p>
      <p> Galanta</p>
      <p> Fantasy</p>
      <p> 59</p>
      <p> 61 62 64 70 71 73</p>
      <p> to Joseph LeSueur</p>
      <p> Some of these poems have appeared previously in  Yugen, Evergreen Review, Poetry, Locus Solus, The Beat Scene, Big Table, Signal, Nugget, The Floating Bear, C, The New American Poetry,  and  City Lights Journal,  to all of whom the author and publisher offer their thanks.</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-7"/>
      <p> MUSIC</p>
      <p> If I rest for a moment near The Equestrian pausing for a liver sausage sandwich in the Mayflower Shoppe, that angel seems to be leading the horse into Bergdorf's and I am naked as a table cloth, my nerves humming. Close to the fear of war and the stars which have disappeared. I have in my hands only 35c, it's so meaningless to eat! and gusts of water spray over the basins of leaves like the hammers of a glass pianoforte. If I seem to you to have lavender lips under the leaves of the world,</p>
      <p> I must tighten my belt. It's like a locomotive on the march, the season</p>
      <p> of distress and clarity and my door is open to the evenings of midwinter's lightly falling snow over the newspapers. Clasp me in your handkerchief like a tear, trumpet of early afternoon ! in the foggy autumn. As they're putting up the Christmas trees on Park Avenue I shall see my daydreams walking by with dogs in blankets, put to some use before all those coloured lights come on !</p>
      <p> But no more fountains and no more rain,</p>
      <p> and the stores stay open terribly late.</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-8"/>
      <p> ALMA</p>
      <p> "Est-elle almee? . . . aux premieres heures bleues Se detruira-t-elle comme les fleurs feues.  . . /'</p>
      <p> — Rimbaud.</p>
      <p> 1</p>
      <p> The sun, perhaps three of them, one black one red, you know, and her dancing all the time, fanning the purple sky getting purple, her fancy white skin quite unoriental to the dirty children's round eyes standing in circles munching muffins, the cockroaches like nuggets half hid in the bran. Boy! how are you, Prester John ? the smile of the river, so searching, so enamelled.</p>
      <p> 2</p>
      <p> What mention of the King ? the spinning wheel still turns, the apples rot to the singing. Ale est e  on winter sojourns</p>
      <p> is nice at Nice. Wander, my dear sacred Pontiff, do dare to murder minutely and ponder what is the bloody affair</p>
      <p> inside the heart of the weak dancer, whose one toe is worth inestimable, the gang, the cheek of it! it's too dear, her birth</p>
      <p> amidst the acorns with nails stuck through them by passionate</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-9"/>
      <p> parents, castanets ! Caucasian tales ! their prodigality proportionate :</p>
      <p> "Sacred Heart, oh Heart so sick, make Detroit more wholly thine, all with greeds and scabs so thick that Judas Priest must make a sign."</p>
      <p> Thus he to bed and we to rise</p>
      <p> and Alma singing like a loon.</p>
      <p> Her dancing toenails in her eyes.</p>
      <p> Her pa was dead on the River Gaboon.</p>
      <p> 3</p>
      <p> Detroit  was founded on the great near waterways next to Canada which was friendly and immediately gained for herself the appellation "the Detroit of Thermopylaes", a name which has stuck to this day wherever ballroom dancing is held in proper esteem. Let me remind you of that great wrist movement, the enjambement schizophrene, a particularly satisfying variation of which may be made by adding a little tomato paste. Great success. While in Detroit accused of starting the Chicago fire. Millions of roses from Russians. Alma had come a long way, she opened a jewelry shop, her name became a household word, she'd invented an arch-supporter.</p>
      <p> How often she thought of her father! the castle, the kitchen-garden, the hollihocks and the mill stream beyond curving gently as a parenthesis. Many a bitter tear was shed by her on the boards of this theatre as she pondered the inscrutable meagerness of divine Providence, always humming, always shifting a little, never missing a beat. She guested one season at the height of her nostalgia with the Metropolitan Opera Ballet in  Salammbo;  her</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-10"/>
      <p> father seemed very close in all that oriental splendor of bamboo and hotel palms and stale sweat and bracelets, an engagement of tears. In the snow, in her white fox fur wraps, how more beautiful than Mary Garden!</p>
      <p> 4</p>
      <p> Onward to the West. *'Where I came from, where I'm going. Indian country." Gold. Oh say can you see Alma. The darling of Them. All her friends were artists. They alone have memories. They alone love flowers. They alone give parties and die. Poor Alma. They alone.</p>
      <p> She died, and it was as if all the jewels in the world had heaved a sigh. The seismograph at Fordham University registered, for once, a spiritual note. How like a sliver in her own short fat muscular foot. She loved the Western World, though there are some who say she isn't really dead.</p>
      <p> 1953</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-11"/>
      <p> n ON RACHMANINOFFS BIRTHDAY</p>
      <p> Quick ! a last poem before I go</p>
      <p> off my rocker. Oh Rachmaninoff!</p>
      <p> Onset, Massachusetts. Is it the fig-newton</p>
      <p> playing the horn ? Thundering windows</p>
      <p> of hell, will your tubes ever break</p>
      <p> into powder ? Oh my palace of oranges,</p>
      <p> junk shop, staples, umber, basalt;</p>
      <p> I'm a child again when I was really</p>
      <p> miserable, a grope pizzicato. My pocket</p>
      <p> of rhinestone, yoyo, carpenter's pencil,</p>
      <p> amethyst, hypo, campaign button,</p>
      <p> is the room full of smoke ? Shit</p>
      <p> on the soup, let it burn. So it's back.</p>
      <p> You'll never be mentally sober.</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-12"/>
      <p> POEM</p>
      <p> I watched an armory combing its bronze bricks and in the sky there were glistening rails of milk. Where had the swan gone, the one with the lame back ?</p>
      <p> Now mounting the steps I enter my new home full of grey radiators and glass ashtrays full of wool.</p>
      <p> Against the winter I must get a samovar embroidered with basil leaves and Ukranian mottos to the distant sound of wings, painfully anti-wind,</p>
      <p> a little bit of the blue summer air will come back as the steam chuckles in the monster's steamy attack</p>
      <p> and I'll be happy here and happy there, full of tea and tears. I don't suppose I'll ever get to Italy, but I have the terrible tundra at least.</p>
      <p> My new home will be full of wood, roots and the like, while I pace in a turtleneck sweater, repairing my bike.</p>
      <p> I watched the palisades shivering in the snow</p>
      <p> of my face, which had grown preternaturally pure.</p>
      <p> Once I destroyed a man's idea of himself to have him.</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-13"/>
      <p> If I'd had a samovar then I'd have made him tea and as hyacinths grow from a pot he would love me</p>
      <p> and my charming room of tea cosies full of dirt which is why I must travel, to collect the leaves. O my enormous piano, you are not like being outdoors</p>
      <p> though it is cold and you are made of fire and wood ! I lift your lid and mountains return, that I am good.</p>
      <p> The stars blink like a hairnet that was dropped on a seat and now it is lying in the alley behind the theater where my play is echoed by dying voices.</p>
      <p> I am really a woodcarver and my words are love which willfully parades in its room, refusing to move.</p>
      <p> 1954</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-14"/>
      <p> ON THE WAY TO SAN REMO</p>
      <p> The black ghinkos snarl their way up</p>
      <p> the moon growls at each bhnking window</p>
      <p> the apartment houses climb deafeningly into the purple</p>
      <p> A bat hisses northwards</p>
      <p> the perilous steps lead to a grate</p>
      <p> suddenly the heat is bearable</p>
      <p> The cross-eyed dog scratches a worn patch of pavement</p>
      <p> his right front leg is maimed in the shape of a V</p>
      <p> there's no trace of his nails on the street a woman cajoles</p>
      <p> She is very old and dirty she whistles her filthy hope that it will rain tonight</p>
      <p> Tlie 6th Avenue bus trunk-lumbers sideways it is full of fat people who cough as at a movie they eat each other's dandruff in the flickering glare</p>
      <p> The moon passes into clouds so hurt by the street lights of your glance oh my heart</p>
      <p> The act of love is also passing like a subway bison through the paper-littered arches of the express tracks the sailor sobers he feeds pennies to the peanut machines</p>
      <p> Though others are in the night far away lips upon a dusty armpit the nostrils are full of tears</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-15"/>
      <p> High fidelity reposed in a box a hand on the windowpane the sweet calm the violin strings tie a young man's hair the bright black eyes pin far away their smudged curiosity</p>
      <p> Yes you are foolish smoking the bars are for rabbits who wish to outlive the men</p>
      <p> 1954</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-16"/>
      <p> 2 POEMS FROM THE OHARA MONOGATARI</p>
      <p> 1</p>
      <p> My love is coming in a glass the  blood of the Bourbons</p>
      <p> saxophone or cornet qu'importe ou?</p>
      <p> green of glass flowers dans le Kentucky</p>
      <p> and always the same handkerchief at the same nose of damask</p>
      <p> turning up my extravagant collar tossing my scarf about my neck</p>
      <p> the Baudelaire of Kyoto's never-ending pureness is he cracked in the head ?</p>
      <p> 2</p>
      <p> After a long trip to a shrine in wooden clogs so hard on the muscles the tea is bitter and the breasts are hard so much terrace for one evening</p>
      <p> there is no longer no ocean</p>
      <p> I don't see the ocean under niy stilts</p>
      <p> as  I poke along</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-17"/>
      <p> hands on ankles feet on wrists</p>
      <p> naked in thought</p>
      <p> like a whip made from sheerest stockings</p>
      <p> the radio is on the cigarette is puffed upon</p>
      <p> by the pleasures of rolling in a bog</p>
      <p> some call the Milky Way</p>
      <p> in far-fetched Occidental lands above  the trees</p>
      <p> where dwell the amusing skulls</p>
      <p> 1954</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-18"/>
      <p> A STEP AWAY FROM THEM</p>
      <p> It's my lunch hour, so I go</p>
      <p> for a walk among the hum-colored</p>
      <p> cabs. First, down the sidewalk</p>
      <p> where laborers feed their dirty</p>
      <p> glistening torsos sandwiches</p>
      <p> and Coca-Cola, with yellow helmets</p>
      <p> on. They protect them from falling</p>
      <p> bricks, I guess. Then onto the</p>
      <p> avenue where skirts are flipping</p>
      <p> above heels and blow up over</p>
      <p> grates. The sun is hot, but the</p>
      <p> cabs stir up the air. I look</p>
      <p> at bargains in wristwatches. There</p>
      <p> are cats playing in sawdust.</p>
      <p> On to Times Square, where the sign blows smoke over my head, and higher the waterfall pours lightly. A Negro stands in a doorway with a toothpick, languorously agitating. A blonde chorus girl clicks : he smiles and rubs his chin. Everything suddenly honks : it is 12 :40 of a Thursday.</p>
      <p> Neon in daylight is a great pleasure, as Edwin Denby would write, as are light bulbs in daylight. I stop for a cheeseburger at JULIET'S CORNER. Giulietta Masina, wife of Federico Fellini,  e bell' attrice.</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-19"/>
      <p> And chocolate malted. A lady in foxes on such a day puts her poodle in a cab.</p>
      <p> There are several Puerto Ricans on the avenue today, which makes it beautiful and warm. First Bunny died, then John Latouche, then Jackson Pollock. But is the earth as full as life was full, of them? And one has eaten and one walks, past the magazines with nudes and the posters for BULLFIGHT and the Manhattan Storage Warehouse, which they'll soon tear down. I used to think they had the Armory Show there.</p>
      <p> A glass of papaya juice and back to work. My heart is in my pocket, it is Poems by Pierre Reverdy.</p>
      <p> 1956</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-20"/>
      <p> CAMBRIDGE</p>
      <p> It is still raining and the yellow-green cotton fruit</p>
      <p> looks silly round a window giving out on winter trees</p>
      <p> with only three drab leaves left. The hot plate works,</p>
      <p> it is the sole heat on earth, and instant coffee. I</p>
      <p> put on my warm corduroy pants, a heavy maroon sweater,</p>
      <p> and wrap myself in my old maroon bathrobe. Just like Pasternak</p>
      <p> in Marburg (they say Italy and France are colder, but</p>
      <p> I'm sure that Germany's at least as cold as this) and,</p>
      <p> lacking the Master's inspiration, I may freeze to death</p>
      <p> before I can get out into the white rain. I could have left</p>
      <p> the window closed last night ? But that's where health</p>
      <p> comes from ! His breath from the Urals, drawing me into flame</p>
      <p> like a forgotten cigarette. Burn ! this is not negligible,</p>
      <p> being poetic, and not feeble, since it's sponsored by</p>
      <p> the greatest living Russian poet at incalculable cost.</p>
      <p> Across the street there is a house under construction,</p>
      <p> abandoned to the rain. Secretly, I shall go to work on it.</p>
      <p> 1956</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-21"/>
      <p> 21 POEM</p>
      <p> Instant coffee with slightly sour cream</p>
      <p> in it, and a phone call to the beyond</p>
      <p> which doesn't seem to be coming any nearer.</p>
      <p> " Ah daddy, I wanna stay drunk many days "</p>
      <p> on the poetry of a new friend</p>
      <p> my life held precariously in the seeing</p>
      <p> hands of others, their and my impossibilities.</p>
      <p> Is this love, now that the first love</p>
      <p> has finally died, where there were no impossibilities ?</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-22"/>
      <p> THREE AIRS</p>
      <p> to Norman Bluhm 1.</p>
      <p> So many things in the air ! soot, elephant balls, a Chinese cloud which is entirely collapsed, a cat swung by its tail</p>
      <p> and the senses of the dead which are banging about inside my tired red eyes</p>
      <p> 2.</p>
      <p> In the deeps there is a little bird and it only hums, it hums of fortitude</p>
      <p> and temperance, it is managing a foundry</p>
      <p> how firmly it must grasp things ! tear them out of the slime and then, alas ! it mischievously</p>
      <p> drops them into the cauldron of hideousness</p>
      <p> there is already a sunset naming</p>
      <p> the poplars which see only, watery, themselves</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-23"/>
      <p> 3.</p>
      <p> Oh to be an angel (if there were any!), and go</p>
      <p> straight up into the sky and look around and then come down</p>
      <p> not to be covered with steel and aluminum glaringly ugly in the pure distances and clattering and</p>
      <p> buckling, wheezing</p>
      <p> but to be part of the treetops and the blueness, invisible, the iridescent darknesses beyond,</p>
      <p> silent, listening to the air becoming no air becoming air again</p>
      <p> 1958</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-24"/>
      <p> IMAGE OF THE BUDDHA PREACHING</p>
      <p> I am very happy to be here at the Villa Hiigel</p>
      <p> and Prime Minister Nehru has asked me to greet the people of</p>
      <p> Essen and to tell you how powerfully affected we in India have been by Germany's philosophy, traditions and mythology though our lucidity and our concentration on archetypes puts us in a class by ourself</p>
      <p> " for in this world of storm and stress " — 5,000 years of Indian art! just think of it, oh Essen ! is this a calmer region of thought, " a reflection of the mind through the ages " ?</p>
      <p> Max Miiller, " primus inter pares " among</p>
      <p> Indologists remember our byword, Mokshamula, I rejoice in the fact of 900</p>
      <p> exhibits</p>
      <p> I deeply appreciate filling the gaps, oh Herr Doktor Heinrich</p>
      <p> Goetz! and the research purring onward in Pakistan and Ceylon and</p>
      <p> Afghanistan soapstone, terracotta-Indus, terracotta-Maurya, terracotta Sunga, terracotta-Andhra, terracotta fragments famous Bharhut</p>
      <p> Stupa Kushana, Ghandara, Gupta, Hindu and Jain, Secco, Ajanta,</p>
      <p> Villa Hugel!</p>
      <p> Anglo-German trade will prosper by Swansea-Mannheim</p>
      <p> friendship waning now the West Wall by virtue of two rolls per capita and the flagship BERLIN is joining its "white fleet" on the Rhine</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-25"/>
      <p> though better schools and model cars are wanting, still still oh</p>
      <p> Essen Nataraja dances on the dwarf and unlike their fathers Germany's highschool pupils love the mathematics</p>
      <p> which is hopeful of a new delay in terror I don't think</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-26"/>
      <p> SONG</p>
      <p> Is it dirty</p>
      <p> does it look dirty</p>
      <p> that's what you think of in the city</p>
      <p> does it just seem dirty</p>
      <p> that's what you think of in the city</p>
      <p> you don't refuse to breathe do you</p>
      <p> someone comes along with a very bad character he seems attractive, is he really, yes. very he's attractive as his character is bad. is it. yes</p>
      <p> that's what you think of in the city</p>
      <p> run your finger along your no-moss mind</p>
      <p> that's not a thought that's soot</p>
      <p> and you take a lot of dirt off someone</p>
      <p> is the character less bad. no. it improves constantly</p>
      <p> you don't refuse to breathe do you</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-27"/>
      <p> 27 THE DAY LADY DIED</p>
      <p> It is 12 : 20 in New York a Friday</p>
      <p> three days after Bastille day, yes</p>
      <p> it is 1959 and I go get a shoeshine</p>
      <p> because I will get off the 4 : 19 in Easthampton</p>
      <p> at 7 : 15 and then go straight to dinner</p>
      <p> and I don't know the people who will feed me</p>
      <p> I walk up the muggy street beginning to sun</p>
      <p> and have a hamburger and a malted and buy</p>
      <p> an ugly NEW WORLD WRITING to see what the poets</p>
      <p> in Ghana are doing these days</p>
      <p> I go on to the bank and Miss Stillwagon (first name Linda I once heard) doesn't even look up my balance for once in her life and in the GOLDEN GRIFFIN I get a little Verlaine for Patsy with drawings by Bonnard although I do think of Hesiod, trans. Richmond Lattimore or Brendan Behan's new play or  Le Balcon  or  I.es Negres of Genet, but I don't, I stick with Verlaine after practically going to sleep with quandariness</p>
      <p> and for Mike I just stroll into the PARK LANE</p>
      <p> Liquor Store and ask for a bottle of Strega and</p>
      <p> then I go back where I came from to 6th Avenue</p>
      <p> and the tobacconist in the Ziegfeld Theatre and</p>
      <p> casually ask for a carton of Gauloises and a carton</p>
      <p> of Picayunes, and a NEW YORK POST with her face on it</p>
      <p> and I am sweating a lot by now and thinking of</p>
      <p> leaning on the John door in the 5 SPOT</p>
      <p> while she whispered a song along the keyboard</p>
      <p> to Mai Waldron and everyone and I stopped breathing</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-28"/>
      <p> POEM</p>
      <p> Wouldn't it be funny</p>
      <p> if The Finger had designed us</p>
      <p> to shit just once a week ?</p>
      <p> all week long we'd get fatter</p>
      <p> and fatter and then on Sunday morning</p>
      <p> while everyone's in church</p>
      <p> ploop!</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-29"/>
      <p> 29 POEM</p>
      <p> Khrushchev is coming on the right day !</p>
      <p> the cool graced light is pushed off the enormous glass piers by hard wind and everything is tossing, hurrying on up</p>
      <p> this country has everything but  politesse,  a Puerto Rican cab driver says and five different girls I see</p>
      <p> look like Piedie Gimbel v^ith her blonde hair tossing too,</p>
      <p> as she looked w^hen I pushed her little daughter on the swing on the lawn it was also windy</p>
      <p> last night we went to a movie and came out,</p>
      <p> lonesco is greater than Beckett, Vincent said, that's what I think, blueberry blintzes and Khrushchev was probably being carped at</p>
      <p> in Washington, no</p>
      <p> politesse Vincent tells me about his mother's trip to Sweden</p>
      <p> Hans tells us about his father's life in Sweden, it sounds like Grace Hartigan's painting  Sweden</p>
      <p> so I go home to bed and names drift through my</p>
      <p> head Purgatorio Merchado, Gerhard Schwartz and Gaspar Gonzales, all unknown figures of the early morning as I go to work</p>
      <p> where does the evil of the year go</p>
      <p> when September takes New York and turns it into ozone stalagmites</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-30"/>
      <p> deposits of light so I get back up make coffee, and read Francois Villon, his life, so dark</p>
      <p> New York seems blinding and my tie is blowing up the street I wish it would blow off</p>
      <p> though it is cold and somewhat warms</p>
      <p> my neck as the train bears Khrushchev on to Pennsylvania Station and the light seems to be eternal and joy seems to be inexorable I am foolish enough always to find it in wind</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-31"/>
      <p> 31 NAPHTHA</p>
      <p> Ah Jean Dubuffet</p>
      <p> when you think of him</p>
      <p> doing his mihtary service in the Eiffel Tower</p>
      <p> as a meteorologist</p>
      <p> in 1922</p>
      <p> you know how wonderful the 20th Century</p>
      <p> can be</p>
      <p> and the gaited Iroquois on the girders</p>
      <p> fierce and unflinching-footed</p>
      <p> nude as they should be</p>
      <p> slightly empty</p>
      <p> like a Sonia Delaunay</p>
      <p> there is a parable of speed</p>
      <p> somewhere behind the Indians' eyes</p>
      <p> they invented the century with their horses</p>
      <p> and their fragile backs</p>
      <p> which are dark</p>
      <p> we owe a debt to the Iroquois</p>
      <p> and to Duke Ellington</p>
      <p> for playing in the buildings when they are built</p>
      <p> we don't do much ourselves</p>
      <p> but fuck and think</p>
      <p> of the haunting Metro</p>
      <p> and the one who didn't show up there</p>
      <p> while we were waiting to become part of our century</p>
      <p> just as you can't make a hat out of steel</p>
      <p> and still wear it</p>
      <p> who wears hats anyway</p>
      <p> it is our tribe's custom</p>
      <p> to beguile</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-32"/>
      <p> how are you feeling in ancient September</p>
      <p> I am feeling like a truck on a wet highway</p>
      <p> how can you</p>
      <p> you were made in the image of god</p>
      <p> I was not</p>
      <p> I was made in the image of a sissy truck-driver</p>
      <p> and Jean Dubuffet painting his cows</p>
      <p> "with a likeness burst in the memory"</p>
      <p> apart from love (don't say it)</p>
      <p> I am ashamed of my century</p>
      <p> for being so entertaining</p>
      <p> but I have to smile</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-33"/>
      <p> PERSONAL POEM</p>
      <p> Now when I walk around at lunchtime I have only two charms in my pocket an old Roman coin Mike Kanemitsu gave me and a bolt-head that broke off a packing case when I was in Madrid the others never brought me too much luck though they did help keep me in New York against coercion but now I'm happy for a time and interested</p>
      <p> I walk through the luminous humidity passing the House of Seagram with its wet and its loungers and the construction to the left that closed the sidewalk if I ever get to be a construction worker I'd like to have a silver hat please and get to Moriarty's where I wait for LeRoi and hear who wants to be a mover and shaker the last five years my batting average is .016 that's that, and LeRoi comes in and tells me Miles Davis was clubbed 12 times last night outside BIRDLAND by a cop a lady asks us for a nickel for a terrible disease but we don't give her one we don't like terrible diseases, then</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-34"/>
      <p> we go eat some fish and some ale it's</p>
      <p> cool but crowded we don't like Lionel Trilling</p>
      <p> we decide, we like Don Allen we don't like</p>
      <p> Henry James so much we like Herman Melville</p>
      <p> we don't want to be in the poets' walk in</p>
      <p> San Francisco even we just want to be rich</p>
      <p> and walk on girders in our silver hats</p>
      <p> I wonder if one person out of the 8,000,000 is</p>
      <p> thinking of me as I shake hands with LeRoi</p>
      <p> and buy a strap for my wristwatch and go</p>
      <p> back to work happy at the thought possibly so</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-35"/>
      <p> ADIEU TO NORMAN, BON JOUR TO JOAN AND JEAN-PAUL</p>
      <p> It is 12 : 10 in New York and I am wondering</p>
      <p> if I will finish this in time to meet Norman for lunch</p>
      <p> ah lunch ! I think I am going crazy</p>
      <p> what with my terrible hangover and the weekend coming up</p>
      <p> at excitement-prone Kenneth Koch's</p>
      <p> I wish I were staying in town and working on my poems</p>
      <p> at Joan's studio for a new book by Grove Press</p>
      <p> which they will probably not print</p>
      <p> but it is good to be several floors up in the dead of night</p>
      <p> wondering whether you are any good or not</p>
      <p> and the only decision you can make is that you did it</p>
      <p> yesterday I looked up the rue Fremicourt on a map</p>
      <p> and was happy to find it like a bird</p>
      <p> flying over Paris et ses environs</p>
      <p> which unfortunately did not include Seine-et-Oise</p>
      <p> which I don't know as well as a number of other things and Allen is back talking about god a lot and Peter is back not talking very much and Joe has a cold and is not coming to Kenneth's although he is coming to lunch with Norman I suspect he is making a distinction well, who isn't</p>
      <p> I wish I were reeling around Paris</p>
      <p> instead of reeling around New York</p>
      <p> I wish I weren't reeling at all</p>
      <p> it is Spring the ice has melted the Ricard is being poured</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-36"/>
      <p> we are all happy and young and toothless</p>
      <p> it is the same as old age</p>
      <p> the only thing to do is simply continue</p>
      <p> is that simple</p>
      <p> yes, it is simple because it is the only thing to do</p>
      <p> can you do it</p>
      <p> yes, you can because it is the only thing to do</p>
      <p> blue light over the Bois de Boulogne it continues</p>
      <p> the Seine continues</p>
      <p> the Louvre stays open it continues it hardly closes at all</p>
      <p> the Bar Americain continues to be French</p>
      <p> de Gaulle continues to be Algerian as does Camus</p>
      <p> Shirley Goldfarb continues to be Shirley Goldfarb</p>
      <p> and Jane Hazan continues to be Jane Freilicher (I think !)</p>
      <p> and Irving Sandler continues to be the balayeur des artistes</p>
      <p> and so do I (sometimes I think I'm "in love" with painting)</p>
      <p> and surely the Piscine Deligny continues to have water in it</p>
      <p> and the Flore continues to have tables and newspapers</p>
      <p> and people under them and surely we shall not continue to be unhappy we shall be happy but we shall continue to be ourselves everything</p>
      <p> continues to be possible Rene Char, Pierre Reverdy, Samuel Beckett it is possible isn't it I love Reverdy for saying yes, though I don't believe it</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-37"/>
      <p> 37 RHAPSODY</p>
      <p> 515 Madison Avenue</p>
      <p> door to heaven ? portal   i</p>
      <p> stopped realities and eternal licentiousness   1</p>
      <p> or at least the jungle of impossible eagerness   \</p>
      <p> your marble is bronze and your lianas elevator cables   ,</p>
      <p> swinging from the myth of ascending   .</p>
      <p> I would join   ;</p>
      <p> or declining the challenge of racial attractions</p>
      <p> they zing on (into the lynch, dear friends)</p>
      <p> while everywhere love is breathing draftily</p>
      <p> like a doorway linking 53rd with 54th</p>
      <p> the east-bound with the west-bound traffic by 8,000,000s</p>
      <p> o midtown tunnels and the tunnels, too, of Holland   I</p>
      <p> where is the summit where all aims are clear</p>
      <p> the pin-point light upon a fear of lust</p>
      <p> as agony's needlework grows up around the unicorn</p>
      <p> and fences him for milk- and yoghurt-work</p>
      <p> when I see Gianni I know he's thinking of John Ericson</p>
      <p> playing the Rachmaninoff 2nd or Elizabeth Taylor</p>
      <p> taking sleeping-pills and Jane thinks of Manderley</p>
      <p> and Irkutsk while I cough lightly in the smog of desire</p>
      <p> and my eyes water achingly imitating the true blue</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-38"/>
      <p> a sight of Manahatta in the towering needle multi-faceted insight of the fiy in the stringless labyrinth Canada plans a higher place than the Empire State Building I am getting into a cab at 9th Street and 1st Avenue and the Negro driver tells me about a $120 apartment "where you can't walk across the floor after 10 at night not even to pee, cause it keeps them awake downstairs" no, I don't like that "well, I didn't take it" perfect in the hot humid morning on my way to work a little supper-club conversation for the mill of the gods</p>
      <p> you were there always and you know all about these things</p>
      <p> as indifferent as an encyclopedia with your calm brown eyes</p>
      <p> it isn't enough to smile when you run the gauntlet</p>
      <p> you've got to spit like Niagara Falls on everybody or</p>
      <p> Victoria Falls or at least the beautiful urban fountains of Madrid</p>
      <p> as the Niger joins the Gulf of Guinea near the Menemsha Bar</p>
      <p> that is what you learn in the early morning passing</p>
      <p> Madison Avenue where you've never spent any time and stores eat up light</p>
      <p> I have always wanted to be near it</p>
      <p> though the day is long (and I don't mean Madison Avenue)</p>
      <p> lying in a hammock on St. Mark's Place sorting my poems</p>
      <p> in the rancid nourishment of this mountainous island</p>
      <p> they are coming and we holy ones must go</p>
      <p> is Tibet historically a part of China? as I historically</p>
      <p> belong to the enormous bliss of American death</p>
      <p> 1959</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-39"/>
      <p> 39 HOTEL PARTICULIER</p>
      <p> How exciting it is</p>
      <p> not to be at Port Lligat or learning Portuguese in Bilbao so you can go to Brazil</p>
      <p> Erik Satie made a great mistake learning Latin the Brise Marine wasn't written in Sanskrit, baby</p>
      <p> I had a teacher one whole summer who never told me anything</p>
      <p> and it was wonderful</p>
      <p> and then there is the Bibliotheque Nationale, cuspidors, glasses, anxiety</p>
      <p> you don't get crabs that way, and what you don't know will hurt somebody else</p>
      <p> how clear the air is, how low the moon, how flat the sun, et cetera,</p>
      <p> just so you don't coin a phrase that changes can be "rung" on</p>
      <p> like les neiges d'antan and that sort of thing (oops !), (roll me over)!</p>
      <p> is this the hostel where the lazy and fun-loving start up the mountain?</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-40"/>
      <p> CORNKIND</p>
      <p> So the  rain falls</p>
      <p> it drops all over the place</p>
      <p> and where it finds a little  rock pool</p>
      <p> it  fills it up with dirt</p>
      <p> and the com grows</p>
      <p> a green Bette Davis sits under it</p>
      <p> reading a volume of William Morris</p>
      <p> oh fertility ! beloved of the Western world</p>
      <p> you aren't so popular in China</p>
      <p> though they fuck too</p>
      <p> and do I really want a son</p>
      <p> to carry on my idiocy past the Homed Gates</p>
      <p> poor kid   a staggering load</p>
      <p> yet it can happen casually</p>
      <p> and he lifts a little of the load each day</p>
      <p> as I become more and more idiotic</p>
      <p> and grows to be a strong strong man</p>
      <p> and one day carries as I die</p>
      <p> my final idiocy and the very gates</p>
      <p> into a future of his choice</p>
      <p> but what of William Morris</p>
      <p> what of you Million Worries</p>
      <p> what of Bette Davis in</p>
      <p> AN EVENING  WITH WILLIAM MORRIS</p>
      <p> or THE WORLD OF SAMUEL GREENBERG</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-41"/>
      <p> what of Hart Crane</p>
      <p> what of phonograph records and gin</p>
      <p> what of "what of"</p>
      <p> you are of me, that's what</p>
      <p> and that's the meaning of fertility</p>
      <p> hard and moist and moaning</p>
      <p> 1960</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-42"/>
      <p> HOW TO GET THERE</p>
      <p> White the October air, no snow, easy to breathe</p>
      <p> beneath the sky, lies, Ues everywhere writhing and gasping</p>
      <p> clutching and tangUng, it is not easy to breathe</p>
      <p> hes building their tendrils into dim figures</p>
      <p> who disappear down corridors in west-side apartments</p>
      <p> into childhood's proof of being wanted, not abandoned, kidnapped</p>
      <p> betrayal staving off loneliness, I see the fog lunge in</p>
      <p> and hide it</p>
      <p> where are you?</p>
      <p> here I am on the sidewalk under the moonlike lamplight thinking how precious moss is so unique and greenly crushable if you can find it on the north side of the tree where the fog binds you and then, tearing apart into soft white lies, spreads its disease through the primal night of an everlasting winter which nevertheless has heat in tubes, west-side and east-side and its intricate individual pathways of white accompanied by the ringing of telephone bells beside which someone sits in silence denying their own number, never given out! nameless like the sound of troika bells rushing past suffering in the first storm, it is snowing now, it is already too late the snow will go away, but nobody will be there</p>
      <p> police cordons for lying political dignitaries ringing too the world becomes a jangle</p>
      <p> from the index finger to the vast empty houses filled with people, their echoes</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-43"/>
      <p> of lies and the tendrils of fog trailing softly around their throats now the phone can be answered, nobody calling, only an echo all can confess to be home and waiting, all is the same and we drift into the clear sky enthralled by our disappointment never to be alone again</p>
      <p> never to be loved sailing through space : didn't I have you once for my self?</p>
      <p> West Side? for a couple of hours, but I am not that person</p>
      <p> 1960</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-44"/>
      <p> A LITTLE TRAVEL DIARY</p>
      <p> Wending our way through the gambas, angulas, the merluzas that taste like the Sea Post on Sunday and the great quantities of huevos they take off Spanish Naval officers' uniforms and put on plates, and reach the gare de Francia in the gloaming with my ton of books and John's ton of clothes bought in a wild fit of enthusiasm in Madrid; all jumbled together like life is a Jumble Shop</p>
      <p> of the theatre in Spain they said nothing for foreigners and we head in our lovely 1st class coach, shifting and sagging, towards the northwest, while in other compartments Dietrich and Erich von Stroheim share a sandwich of chorizos and a bottle of Vichy Catalan, in the dining car the travelling gentleman with linear mustache and many many rings rolls his cigar around and drinks Martini y ginebra, and Lillian Gish rolls on over the gorges with a tear in her left front eye, comme Picasso, through the night through the night, longitudinous and affected with stars; the riverbeds so far below look as a pig's tongue on a platter, and storms break over San Sebastian, 40 foot waves drench us pleasantly and we see a dead dog bloated as a fraise lolling beside the quai and slowly pulling out to sea</p>
      <p> to Irun and Biarritz we go, sapped of anxiety, and there for the first time since arriving in Barcelona I can freely shit and the surf is so high and the sun is so hot and it was all built yesterday as everything should be</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-45"/>
      <p> what a splendid country it is</p>
      <p> full of indecision and cognac and bikinis, sens plastiques (ugh ! hooray !); see the back of the head of Bill Berkson, aux Deux Magots, (awk !) it gleams like the moon through the smoke of the Renfe as we passed through the endless tunnels and the silver vistas of our quest for the rocher de la Vierge and salt spray</p>
      <p> 1960</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-46"/>
      <p> FIVE POEMS</p>
      <p> Well now, hold on</p>
      <p> maybe I won't go to sleep at all</p>
      <p> and it'll be a beautiful white night</p>
      <p> or else I'll collapse</p>
      <p> completely from nerves and be calm</p>
      <p> as a rug or a bottle of pills</p>
      <p> or suddenly I'll be off Montauk</p>
      <p> swimming and loving it and not caring where</p>
      <p> an invitation to lunch</p>
      <p> HOW DO YOU LIKE THAT?</p>
      <p> when I only have 16 cents and 2</p>
      <p> packages of yoghurt</p>
      <p> there's a lesson in that, isn't there</p>
      <p> like in Chinese poetry when a leaf falls?</p>
      <p> hold off on the yoghurt till the very</p>
      <p> last, when everything may improve</p>
      <p> at the Rond-Point they were eating</p>
      <p> a oyster, but here</p>
      <p> we were dropping by sculptures</p>
      <p> and seeing some paintings</p>
      <p> and the smasheroo-grates of Cadoret</p>
      <p> and music by Varese, too</p>
      <p> well Adolph Gottlieb I guess you</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-47"/>
      <p> are the hero of this day along with venison and Bill</p>
      <p> I'll sleep on the yoghurt and dream of the Persian Gulf</p>
      <p> which I did it was wonderful</p>
      <p> to be in bed again and the knock</p>
      <p> on my door for once signified "hi there"</p>
      <p> and on the deafening walk</p>
      <p> through the ghettos where bombs have gone off lately</p>
      <p> left by subway violators</p>
      <p> I knew why I love taxis, yes</p>
      <p> subways are only fun when you're feeling sexy</p>
      <p> and who feels sexy after  The Blue Angel</p>
      <p> well maybe a little bit</p>
      <p> I seem to be defying fate, or am I avoiding it ?</p>
      <p> 1960</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-48"/>
      <p> AVE MARIA</p>
      <p> Mothers of America</p>
      <p> let your kids go to the movies ! get them out of the house so they won't know what you're up to it's true that fresh air is good for the body</p>
      <p> but what about the soul that grows in darkness, embossed by silvery images and when you grow old as grow old you must</p>
      <p> they won't hate you they won't criticise you they won't know</p>
      <p> they'll be in some glamorous country they first saw on a Saturday afternoon or playing hookey</p>
      <p> they may even be grateful to you</p>
      <p> for their first sexual experience which only cost you a quarter</p>
      <p> and didn't upset the peaceful home they will know where candy bars come from</p>
      <p> and gratuitous bags of popcorn as gratuitous as leaving the movie before it's over with a pleasant stranger whose apartment is in the</p>
      <p> Heaven on Earth Bldg near the Williamsburg Bridge</p>
      <p> oh mothers you will have made the little tykes so happy because if nobody does pick them up in the movies they won't know the difference</p>
      <p> and if somebody does it'll be sheer gravy and they'll have been truly entertained either way instead of hanging around the yard</p>
      <p> or up in their room</p>
      <p> hating you</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-49"/>
      <p> prematurely since you won't have done anything horribly</p>
      <p> mean yet except keeping them from the darker joys</p>
      <p> it's unforgivable the latter so don't blame me if you won't take this advice</p>
      <p> and the family breaks up and your children grow old and blind in front of a TV set</p>
      <p> seeing movies you wouldn't let them see when they were young</p>
      <p> 1960</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-50"/>
      <p> PISTACHIO TREE AT CHATEAU NOIR</p>
      <p> Beaucoup de musique classique et moderne Guillaume and not</p>
      <p> as one may imagine it sounds not in the ear</p>
      <p> what went was attributed to wandering aimlessly off</p>
      <p> what came arrived simply for itself and inflamed me</p>
      <p> yet I do not explain what exactly makes me so happy today</p>
      <p> any more than I can explain the unseasonal warmth</p>
      <p> of my unhabitual heart pumping vulgarly the blood</p>
      <p> of another I loved another and now my love is other</p>
      <p> my love is in the movies downstairs and yesterday</p>
      <p> bought ice cream and looked for a pigeon-menaced owl</p>
      <p> mais, Guillaume, ou es-tu, Guillaume, comme les musiques</p>
      <p> and like the set for  Rigoletto  like the set for  Roma like so many sets one's heart is torn like Berman's spacious haunt where tenors walk in pumps and girls in great big hats or none at all "or perhaps he recorded the panorama of hills and valleys before the strangely naked" and rain is turning the set into a dumpling</p>
      <p> wherever I see a "while" I seem to lose a little time and gradually my feet dragging I slow down the damn bus it is because of you so I can watch you smile longer that's what the Spring is and the elbow of noon walks where did you go who did you see the children proclaim and they too gradually fill the sepulchre with dolls and the sepulchre jumps and jounces and turns pink with wrath</p>
      <p> 1961</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-51"/>
      <p> AT KAMIN'S DANCE BOOKSHOP</p>
      <p> to Vincent Warren</p>
      <p> Shade of Fanny Elssler ! I dreamt that you passed over me last</p>
      <p> night in sleep was it you who was asleep or was it me ? sweet shade shade shade shill spade agony freak geek you were not nor were you made of ribbons but of warm</p>
      <p> moving flesh &amp; tulle you were twining your left leg around your right as if your</p>
      <p> right were me I've never felt so wide awake I seemed to be wearing tights entwined with your legs and a</p>
      <p> big sash over my crotch and a jewel in my left ear for luck (to help me balance) and you were pulling me toward the floor</p>
      <p> reaching for stars it seemed to me that I was warm at last and palpable not just a skein of lust dipped in the grand</p>
      <p> appreciation of yours where are you Fanny Elssler come back !</p>
      <p> 1%1</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-52"/>
      <p> STEPS</p>
      <p> How  funny  you are today New York</p>
      <p> like Ginger Rogers in  Swingtime</p>
      <p> and St. Bridget's steeple leaning a little to the left</p>
      <p> here I have just jumped out of a bed full of V-days</p>
      <p> (I got tired of D-days) and blue you there still</p>
      <p> accepts me foolish and free</p>
      <p> all I want is a room up there</p>
      <p> and you in it</p>
      <p> and even the traffic halt so thick is a way</p>
      <p> for people to rub up against each other</p>
      <p> and when their surgical appliances lock</p>
      <p> they stay together</p>
      <p> for the rest of the day (what a day)</p>
      <p> I go by to check a slide and I say</p>
      <p> that painting's not so blue</p>
      <p> where's Lana Turner</p>
      <p> she's out eating</p>
      <p> and Garbo's backstage at the Met</p>
      <p> everyone's taking their coat off</p>
      <p> so they can show a rib-cage to the rib-watchers</p>
      <p> and the park's full of dancers and their tights and shoes</p>
      <p> in little bags</p>
      <p> who are often mistaken  for  worker-outers at the West Side Y</p>
      <p> why not</p>
      <p> the Pittsburgh Pirates shout because they won</p>
      <p> and in a sense we're all winning</p>
      <p> we're alive</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-53"/>
      <p> the apartment was vacated by a gay couple</p>
      <p> who moved to the country for fun</p>
      <p> they moved a day too soon</p>
      <p> even the stabbings are helping the population explosion</p>
      <p> though in the wrong country</p>
      <p> and all those liars have left the U N</p>
      <p> the Seagram Building's no longer rivalled in interest</p>
      <p> not that we need liquor (we just like it)</p>
      <p> and the little box is out on the sidewalk</p>
      <p> next to the delicatessen</p>
      <p> so the old man can sit on it and drink beer</p>
      <p> and get knocked off it by his wife later in the day</p>
      <p> while the sun is still shining</p>
      <p> oh god it's wonderful</p>
      <p> to get out of bed</p>
      <p> and drink too much coffee</p>
      <p> and smoke too many cigarettes</p>
      <p> and love you so much</p>
      <p> 1961</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-54"/>
      <p> MARY DESTI'S ASS</p>
      <p> In Bayreuth once</p>
      <p> we were very good friends of the Wagners</p>
      <p> and I stepped in once</p>
      <p> for Isadora so perfectly</p>
      <p> she would never allow me to dance again</p>
      <p> that's the way it was in Bayreuth</p>
      <p> the way it was in Hackensack</p>
      <p> was different</p>
      <p> there one never did anything</p>
      <p> and everyone hated you anyway</p>
      <p> it was fun, it was clear</p>
      <p> you knew where you stood</p>
      <p> in Boston you were never really standing</p>
      <p> I was usually lying</p>
      <p> it was amusing to be lying all</p>
      <p> the time for everybody</p>
      <p> it was like exercise</p>
      <p> it means something to exercise</p>
      <p> in Norfolk Virginia</p>
      <p> it means you've been to bed with a Nigra</p>
      <p> well it is exercise</p>
      <p> the only difference is it's better than Boston</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-55"/>
      <p> I was walking along the street of Cincinnati</p>
      <p> and I met Kenneth Koch's mother fresh from the Istanbul Hilton she liked me and I liked her we both liked Istanbul</p>
      <p> then in Waukegan I met a furniture manufacturer</p>
      <p> and it wiped out all dreams of pleasantness from my mind</p>
      <p> it was like being pushed down hard</p>
      <p> on a chair</p>
      <p> it was like something horrible you hadn't expected</p>
      <p> which is the most horrible thing</p>
      <p> and in Singapore I got a dreadful disease it was amusing to have bumps except they went into my veins and rose to the surface like Vesuvius getting cured was like learning to smoke</p>
      <p> yet I always loved Baltimore the porches which hurt your ass no, they were the steps well you have a wet ass anyway if they'd only stop scrubbing</p>
      <p> and Frisco where I saw</p>
      <p> Toumanova "the baby ballerina" except</p>
      <p> she looked like a cow</p>
      <p> I didn't know the history of the ballet yet</p>
      <p> not that that taught me much</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-56"/>
      <p> now if you feel like you want to deal with</p>
      <p> Tokyo</p>
      <p> you've really got something to handle</p>
      <p> it's like Times Square at midnight</p>
      <p> you don't know where you're going</p>
      <p> but you know</p>
      <p> and then in Harbin I knew</p>
      <p> how to behave it was glorious that</p>
      <p> was love sneaking up on me through the snow</p>
      <p> and I felt it was because of all</p>
      <p> the postcards and the smiles and kisses and the grunts</p>
      <p> that was love but I kept on traveling</p>
      <p> 1961</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-57"/>
      <p> 57 ST. PAUL AND ALL THAT</p>
      <p> Totally abashed and smiling</p>
      <p> I walk in sit down and face the frigidaire</p>
      <p> it's April</p>
      <p> no May</p>
      <p> it's May</p>
      <p> such little things have to be established in morning after the big things of night</p>
      <p> do you want me to come ? when I think of all the things I've been thinking of I feel insane simply "life in Birmingham is hell"</p>
      <p> simply "you will miss me but that's good" when the tears of a whole generation are assembled they will only fill a coflfee cup</p>
      <p> just because they evaporate doesn't mean life has heat</p>
      <p> "this various dream of living" I am alive with you</p>
      <p> full of anxious pleasures and pleasurable anxiety hardness and softness</p>
      <p> listening while you talk and talking while you read I read what you read</p>
      <p> you do not read what I read which is right, I am the one with the curiosity you read for some mysterious reason</p>
      <p> I read simply because I am a writer the sun doesn't necessarily set, sometimes it just disappears</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-58"/>
      <p> when you're not here someone walks in and says</p>
      <p> "hey, there's no dancer in that bed"</p>
      <p> O the Polish summers ! those drafts ! those black and white teeth ! you never come when you say you'll come but on the other hand</p>
      <p> you do come 1961</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-59"/>
      <p> MEMOIR OF SERGEI O. . . .</p>
      <p> My feet have never been comfortable since I pulled them out of the Black Sea and came to your foul country what fatal day did I dry them off for travel loathesome travel to a world even older than the one I grew up in what fatal day meanwhile back in France they were stumbling towards the Bastille and the Princesse de Lamballe was shuddering as shudderingly as I with a lot less to lose I still hated to move sedentary as a roach of Tiflis never again to go swimming in the nude publicly little did I know how awfulness could reach perfection abroad I even thought I would see a Red Indian all I saw was lipstick everything covered with grass or shrouds pretty shrouds shot with silver and plasma even the chairs are upholstered to a smothering perfection of inanity and there are no chandeliers and there are no gates to the parks so you don't know whether you're going in them or coming out of them that's not relaxing and so you can't really walk all you can do is sit and drink coffee and brood over the lost leaves and refreshing scum of Georgia Georgia of my heritage and dismay meanwhile back in my old</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-60"/>
      <p> country they are renaming everything so I can't even tell any more which ballet company I am remembering with so much pain and the same thing has started here American Avenue Park Avenue South Avenue of Chester Conklin Binnie Barnes Boulevard Avenue of Toby Wing Barbara Nichols Street w here am I what is it I can't even find a pond small enough to drown in without being ostentatious you are ruining your awful country- and me it is not new to do this it is terribly democratic and ordinary and tired</p>
      <p> 1961</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-61"/>
      <p> 61 YESTERDAY DOWN AT THE CANAL</p>
      <p> You say that everything is very simple and interesting</p>
      <p> it makes me feel very wistful, like reading a great Russian novel</p>
      <p> does I am terribly bored sometimes it is like seeing a bad movie other days, more often, it's like having an acute disease of the</p>
      <p> kidney god knows it has nothing to do with the heart nothing to do with people more interesting than myself yak yak</p>
      <p> that's an amusing thought how can anyone be more amusing than oneself how can anyone fail to be can I borrow your forty-five I only need one bullet preferably silver if you can't be interesting at least you can be a legend (but I hate all that crap)</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-62"/>
      <p> POEM EN FORME DE SAW</p>
      <p> I ducked out of sight behind the saw-mill</p>
      <p> nobody saw me because of the falls the gates the sluice the</p>
      <p> tourist boats the children were trailing their fingers in the water and the swans, regal and smarty, were nipping their "little"</p>
      <p> fingers I heard one swan remark "That was a good nip though they are not as interesting as sausages" and another reply "Nor as tasty as those peasants we got away from the</p>
      <p> elephant that time" but I didn't really care for conversation that day I wanted to be alone</p>
      <p> which is why I went to the mill in the first place now I am alone and hate it</p>
      <p> I don't want to just make boards for the rest of my life I'm distressed</p>
      <p> the water is very beautiful but you can't go into it because of the gunk</p>
      <p> and the dog is always rolling over, I like dogs on their "little" feet I think I may scamper off to Winnipeg to see Raymond but what'll happen to the mill I see the cobwebs collecting already and later those other webs, those awful predatory webs if I stay right here I will eventually get into the newspapers like Robert Frost</p>
      <p> willow trees, willow trees they remind me of Desdemona I'm so damned literary and at the same time the waters rushing past remind me of</p>
      <p> nothing I'm so damned empty what is all this vessel shit anyway we are all rushing down the River Happy Times</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-63"/>
      <p> ducking poling bumping sinking and swimming</p>
      <p> and we arrive at the beach</p>
      <p> the chaff is sand</p>
      <p> alone as a tree bumping another tree in a storm</p>
      <p> that's not really being alone, is it, signed The Saw</p>
      <p> 1961</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-64"/>
      <p> FOR THE CHINESE NEW YEAR &amp; FOR BILL BERKSON</p>
      <p> One or another Is lost, since we fall apart Endlessly, in one motion depart From each other. — D. H. Lawrence</p>
      <p> Behind New York there's a face and it's not Sibelius's with a cigar it was red it was strange and hateful and then I became a child again like a nadir or a zenith or a nudnik</p>
      <p> what do you think this is my youth</p>
      <p> and the aged future that is sweeping me away</p>
      <p> earless and gasless under the Sutton</p>
      <p> and Beekman Places towards a hellish rage</p>
      <p> it is there that face I fear under ramps</p>
      <p> it is perhaps the period that ends</p>
      <p> the problem as a proposition of days of days</p>
      <p> just an attack on the feelings that stay</p>
      <p> poised in the hurricane's center that</p>
      <p> eye  through which only camels can pass</p>
      <p> but  I do not mean that tenderness doesn't linger like a Paris afternoon or a wart something dumb and despicable that I love because it is silent oh what difference does it make me into some kind of space statistic</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-65"/>
      <p> a lot is buried under that smile</p>
      <p> a lot of sophistication gone down the drain</p>
      <p> to become the mesh of a mythical fish</p>
      <p> at which we never stare back never stare back</p>
      <p> where there is so much downright forgery</p>
      <p> under that I find it restful like a bush some people are outraged by cleanliness I hate the lack of smells myself and yet I stay it is better than being actually present and the stare can swim away into the past</p>
      <p> can adorn it with easy convictions rat cow tiger rabbit dragon snake horse sheep monkey rooster dog and pig "Flower Drum Song" so that nothing is vain not the gelded sand not the old spangled lotus not my fly</p>
      <p> which I have thought about but never really looked at well that's a certain orderliness of personality "if you're brought up Protestant enough a Catholic" oh shit on the beaches so what if I did look up your trunks and see it</p>
      <p> II</p>
      <p> then the parallel becomes an eagle parade of Busby Berkeleyites marching marching half-toe I suppose it's the happiest moment in infinity because we're dissipated and tired and fond no I don't think psychoanalysis shrinks the spleen</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-66"/>
      <p> here we are and what the hell are we going to do with it we are going to blow it up like daddy did only us I really think we should go up for a change I'm tired of always going down what price glory it's one of those timeless priceless words like come</p>
      <p> well now how does your conscience feel about that would you rather explore tomorrow with a sponge there's no need to look for a target you're it like in childhood when the going was aimed at a sandwich it all depends on which three of us are there</p>
      <p> but here come the prophets with their loosening nails it is only as blue as the lighting under the piles I have something portentous to say to you but which of the papier-mache languages do you understand you don't dare to take it off paper much less put it on</p>
      <p> yes it is strange that everyone fucks and everyone mentions it and it's boring too that faded floor how many teeth have chewed a little piece of the lover's flesh how many teeth are there in the world it's like Harpo Marx smiling at a million pianos call that Africa</p>
      <p> call it New Guinea call it Poughkeepsie I guess</p>
      <p> it's love I guess the season of renunciation is at "hand"</p>
      <p> the final fatal hour of turpitude and logic demise</p>
      <p> is when you miss getting rid of something delouse</p>
      <p> is when you don't louse something up which way is the inn</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-67"/>
      <p> III</p>
      <p> I'm looking for a million-dollar heart in a carton</p>
      <p> of frozen strawberries like the Swedes where is sunny England</p>
      <p> and those fields where they still-birth the wars why</p>
      <p> did they suddenly stop playing why is Venice a Summer</p>
      <p> Festival and not New York were you born in America</p>
      <p> the inscrutable passage of a lawn-mower punctuates the newly installed Muzack in the Shubert Theatre am I nuts or is this the happiest moment of my life who's arguing it's I mean 'tis lawd sakes it took daddy a long time to have that accident so Ant Grace could get completely into black</p>
      <p> didn't you know we was all going to be Zen Buddhists after what we did you sure don't know much about war-guilt or nothin and the peach trees continued to rejoice around the prick which was for once authorized by our Congress though inactive what if it had turned out to be a volcano</p>
      <p> that's a mulatto of another nationality of marble it's time for dessert I don't care what street this is you're not telling me to take a tour are you 1 don't want to look at any fingernails or any toes I just want to go on being subtle and dead like life</p>
      <p> I'm not naturally so detached but I think</p>
      <p> they might send me up any minute so I try to be free</p>
      <p> you know we've all sinned a lot against science</p>
      <p> so we really ought to be available as an apple on a bough</p>
      <p> pleasant thought fresh air free love cross-pollenization</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-68"/>
      <p> oh oh god how I'd love to dream let alone sleep it's night the soft air wraps me like a swarm it's raining and I have a cold I am a real human being with real ascendancies and a certain amount of rapture what do you do with a kid like me if you don't eat me I'll have to eat myself</p>
      <p> it's a strange curse my "generation" has we're all</p>
      <p> like the flowers in the Agassiz Museum perpetually ardent</p>
      <p> don't touch me because when I tremble it makes a noise</p>
      <p> like a Chinese wind-bell it's that I'm seismographic is all</p>
      <p> and when a Jesuit has stared you down for ever after you clink</p>
      <p> I wonder if I've really scrutinized this experience like you're supposed to have if you can type there's not much soup left on my sleeve energy creativity guts ponderableness lent is coming in imponderableness "I'd like to die smiling" ugh and a very small tiptoe is crossing the threshold away</p>
      <p> whither Lumumba whither oh whither Gauguin I have often tried to say goodbye to strange fantoms I read about in the newspapers and have always succeeded though the ones at "home" are dependent on Dependable Laboratory and Sales Company on Pulaski Street strange</p>
      <p> I think it's goodbye to a lot of things like Christmas</p>
      <p> and the Mediterranean and halos and meteorites and villages</p>
      <p> full of damned children well it's goodbye then as in Strauss</p>
      <p> or some other desperately theatrical venture it's goodbye</p>
      <p> to lunch to love to evil things and to the ultimate good as "well"</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-69"/>
      <p> the strange career of a personality begins at five and ends forty minutes later in a fog the rest is just a lot of stranded ships honking their horns full of joy-seeking cadets in bloomers and beards it's okay with me but must they cheer while they honk it seems that breath could easily fill a balloon and drift away</p>
      <p> scaring the locusts in the straggling grey of living dumo exertions then the useful noise would come of doom of data turned to elegant decoration like a strangling prince once ordered no there is no precedent of history no history nobody came before nobody will ever come before and nobody ever was that man</p>
      <p> you will not die not knowing this is true this year</p>
      <p> 1961</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-70"/>
      <p> POEM</p>
      <p> Lana Turner has collapsed !</p>
      <p> I was trotting along and suddenly</p>
      <p> it started raining and snowing</p>
      <p> and you said it was hailing</p>
      <p> but hailing hits you on the head</p>
      <p> hard so it was really snowing and</p>
      <p> raining and I was in such a hurry</p>
      <p> to meet you but the traffic</p>
      <p> was acting exactly like the sky</p>
      <p> and suddenly I see a headline</p>
      <p> LANA TURNER HAS COLLAPSED 1</p>
      <p> there is no snow in Hollywood</p>
      <p> there is no rain in California</p>
      <p> I have been to lots of parties</p>
      <p> and acted perfectly disgraceful</p>
      <p> but I never actually collapsed</p>
      <p> oh Lana Turner we love you get up</p>
      <p> 1962</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-71"/>
      <p> GALANTA</p>
      <p> A Strange den or music room</p>
      <p> childhood dream of Persian grass configured distilled first hardon milky mess</p>
      <p> the about-to-be dead surrounding the already surrounded folk-hero with a veil of automobile accidents broken cocktail glasses</p>
      <p> oh Sally is still acting the mise en scene of her great grandmother's embroidered graveyard while I</p>
      <p> my asiatic tendencies have taken me to the Baghdad of neurasthenia and false objectivity</p>
      <p> faint hope for a familial contrast for a far-reaching decadence which presupposes unnatural unselfishness your sweet yellow hair</p>
      <p> among the mosques the faint tribal twitch of your altered blue eyes</p>
      <p> when Canaan was reached you called me France we threw sand in our eyes and ran naked</p>
      <p> down the street of our awful progenitors</p>
      <p> when life is fantastic there is no chance for make-believe how lucky the French bourgeois pain</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-72"/>
      <p> could be if we were children again and ever^-thing uninteresting you never had a chance to be</p>
      <p> Emma Bovary-nor I Julien Sorel in that attic in the States and now</p>
      <p> I remember you only through American Folk Art opening near the Fonda del Sol where are you Sally with your practicality and bottles of fireflies</p>
      <p> blinking on and oflF for footlights</p>
      <p> 1962</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-73"/>
      <p> 73 FANTASY</p>
      <p> {dedicated to the health of Allen Ginsberg)</p>
      <p> How do you like the music of Adolph</p>
      <p> Deutsch? I like it, I like it better than Max Steiner's. Take his score for  Northern Pursuit,  the Helmut Dantyne theme was . . .</p>
      <p> and then the window fell on my hand. Errol Flynn was skiing by. Down</p>
      <p> down down went the grim grey submarine under the "cold" ice.</p>
      <p> Helmut was safely ashore, on the ice.</p>
      <p> What dreams, what incredible fantasies of snow farts will this all lead to?</p>
      <p> I don't know, I have stopped thinking like a sled dog.</p>
      <p> The main thing is to tell a story.</p>
      <p> It is almost very important. Imagine</p>
      <p> throwing away the avalanche so early in the movie. I am the only spy left in Canada,</p>
      <p> but just because I'm alone in the snow doesn't necessarily mean I'm a Nazi.</p>
      <p> Let's see, two aspirins a vitamin G tablet and some baking soda should do the trick, that's practically an</p>
      <p> Alka</p>
      <div class="newpage" id="page-74"/>
      <p> Seltzer. Allen come out of the bathroom</p>
      <p> and take it. I think someone put butter on my skis instead of wax.</p>
      <p> Ouch. The leanto is falling over in the firs, and there is another fatter spy here. They didn't tell me they sent</p>
      <p> him. Well, that takes care of him, boy were those huskies hungry.</p>
      <p> Allen, are you feeling any better? Yes, I'm crazy about Helmut Dantyne</p>
      <p> but I'm glad that Canada will remain free. Just free, that's all, never argue with the movies.</p>
      <p> 1964</p>
      <p> CITY LIGHTS PUBLICATIONS</p>
      <p> Antler.  FACTORY (Pocket Poets n38)</p>
      <p> Artaud, Antonin.  ANTHOLOGY</p>
      <p> Baudelaire, Charles.  INTIMATE JOURNALS</p>
      <p> Bowles, Paul.  A HUNDRED CAMELS IN THE COURTYARD</p>
      <p> Brea, Juan  Sc  Maiy Low.  RED SPANISH NOTEBOOK</p>
      <p> Brecht, Stefan.  POEMS (Pocket Poets U36)</p>
      <p> Broughton, James.  SEEING THE LIGHT</p>
      <p> Buckley, Lord.  HIPARAMA OF THE CLASSICS</p>
      <p> Bukowski, Charles.  THE MOST BEAUTIFUL WOMAN</p>
      <p> IN TOWN Bukowski, Charles.  NOTES OF A DIRTY OLD MAN Bukowski, Charles.  SHAKESPEARE NEVER DID THIS Bukowski, Charles.  TALES OF ORDINARY MADNESS Burroughs, William S.  THE BURROUGHS FILE Burroughs, William S.  ROOSEVELT AFTER</p>
      <p> INAUGURATION Burroughs, W.S.  Sc  Allen Ginsberg.  THE YAGE LETTERS Cassady, Neal.  THE FIRST THIRD CITY LIGHTS JOURNAL No. 4 Codrescu, Andrei.  IN AMERICA'S SHOES Corso, Gregory.  GASOLINE/VESTAL LADY ON BRATTLE</p>
      <p> (Pocket Poets U8) David Neel, Alexandia.  SECRET ORAL TEACHINGS IN</p>
      <p> TIBETAN BUDDHIST SECTS Di Prima, Diane.  REVOLUTIONARY LETTERS Doolittle, Hilda.  (H.D.) NOTES ON THOUGHT &amp; VISION Duncan, Isadora.  ISADORA SPEAKS Eberhardt, Isabelle.  THE OBLIVION SEEKERS Fenollosa, Ernest.  THE CHINESE WRITTEN CHARACTER</p>
      <p> AS A MEDIUM FOR POETRY Ferlinghetti, Lawrence.  PICTURES OF THE GONE WORLD</p>
      <p> (Pocket Poets UI) FREE SPIRITS: Annals of the Insurgent Imagination</p>
      <p> Gascovne, Da\id.  A SHORT SURVEY OF SURREALISM</p>
      <p> Ginsberg, Allen.  THE FALL OF AMERICA (Pocket Poets UBO)</p>
      <p> Ginsberg, Allen.  HOWL &amp; OTHER POEMS (Pocket Poets M)</p>
      <p> Ginsberg, Allen.  INDIAN JOURNALS</p>
      <p> Ginsberg. Allen.  IRON HORSE</p>
      <p> Ginsberg, Allen.  KADDISH if OTHER POEMS</p>
      <p> (Pocket Poets UH) Ginsberg, Allen.  MIND BREATHS (Pocket Poets  #55j Gnisberg, Allen.  PLANET NEWS (Pocket Poets n23) Ginsberg, Allen.  PLUTONIAN ODE (Pocket Poets U40) Ginsberg, Allen.  REALITY SANDWICHES (Pocket Poets ni8) Hirschman, Jack.  LYRIPOL (Pocket Poets n34) Horowitz, Michael.  BIG LEAGUE POETS JOURNAL FOR THE PROTECTION OF ALL BEINGS No. 4 Kerouac, Jack.  BOOK OF DREAMS Kerouac, Jack.  SCATTERED POEMS (Pocket Poets n28) Lamantia, Philip.  BECOMING VISIBLE (Pocket Poets U39) Lamantia, Philip.  SELECTED POEMS (Pocket Poets U20) Laughlin, James.  IN ANOTHER COUNTRY Lowrv, Malcolm.  SELECTED POEMS (Pocket Poets UI7) Lucebert.  NINE DUTCH POETS (Pocket Poets n42) Ludlow, Fitzhugh.  THE HASHEESH EATER McDonough, Kave.  ZELDA Moore, Daniel.  BURNT HEART Mrabet,^  Mohammed.^M'HASHISH Miirguia, A.  VOLCAN: Poems from Central America Newton, Huey  &amp;:  Ericka Huggins.  INSIGHTS &amp; POEMS O'Haia, Frank.  LUNCH POEMS (Pocket Poets ni9) Olson, Charles.  CALL ME ISHMAEL Orloxskv, Peter.  CLEAN ASSHOLE POEMS t SMILING</p>
      <p> VEGETABLE SONGS (Pocket Poets n37) Patchen, Kenneth.  LOVE POEMS (Pocket Poets UI3) Patchen, Kenneth.  POEMS OF HUMOR 6- PROTEST</p>
      <p> (Pocket Poets n3) Pickard, Tom.  GUTTERSNIPE</p>
      <p> Plymell, Charles.  THE LAST OF THE MOCCASINS Poe, Edgar Allan.  THE UNKNOWN FOE Prevert, Jacques.  FAROLES (Focket Foets n9) Rips, Geoffrey.  UNAMERICAN ACTIVITIES Rosemont, Franklin.  SURREALISM ir ITS</p>
      <p> FOFULAR ACCOMFLICES Sanders, Ed.  INVESTIGATIVE FOETRY Shepaid, Sam.  FOOL FOR LOVE Shepaid, Sam.  MOTEL CHRONICLES Snyder, Gary.  THE OLD WAYS Solomon, Carl.  MISHAFS FERHAFS Solomon, Carl.  MORE MISHAFS Svevo, Italo.  JAMES JOYCE</p>
      <p> Upton, Charles.  FANIC GRASS (Focket Foets U24) Voznesenskv, Andrei.  DOGALYFSE (Focket Foets n29) Waldman, Anne.  FAST SFEAKING WOMAN (Focket Foets U33) Waley, Arthur.  THE NINE SONGS Yevtushenko, Yevgeni.  RED CATS (Focket Foets ni6)</p>
    </div>
  </body>
</html>
